

Mohammad Usman

Mobile: +91-9911665501

Communication Details

H.No.19, 1st Floor, Gali No.18, Jagatpuri, Krishna Nagar, Delhi-110051, India

Email: usmaansaif@gmail.com Skype: live:6688dbcaccb56c64

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To handle highly challenging assignments in areas of Finance & Accounts for a highly growth oriented and reputed organization thereby actively contributing towards the success of organizational goals.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMERY

Having 14 Year of Experience in Accounting and Finance.

Monitoring day to day transactions & maintaining final accounts.

Working knowledge of Zoho Books, Tally ERP, Busy

Skills in relationship management and communication

Coordinating with vendors, bankers etc. for smoother operation

Financial Planning and management as per the need of organization

SKILL SET

General Accounting, Financial Closing, Bank Reconciliation, Invoicing, Budget, MIS Report, Taxation, Payroll, AR, AP, Cash Management, Exchange Report Other Exchange Back office work and daily obligation work etc.

WORK EXPERIENCE

a. Sr. Accounts Executive with Present Media Pvt. Ltd., Gurgaon, Delhi NCR, **India From July 2017 to Present Date.**

Responsibilities:

- Prepares TDS Return and Release TDS Certificates.
- Reconcile GST Return and Filling.
- MIS Reporting (Profitability, Ageing, Cash Flow etc.)
- Prepare and Processing company payroll.
- Bank Reconciliations (Including Overseas Bank)
- Vendor, Client and Intercompany Reconciliation.
- Account Payable and Account Receivable.
- Ledger Scrutiny, Audit, Prepare Financial Books.
- Handling Cash and General Expenses.
- Coordination with CA and for Balance Sheet & ROC Returns.

b. Senior Accounts Executive with Amrapali Aadya Trading & Investment Pvt. Ltd. Delhi, India from October 2015 to June 2017.

Responsibilities:

- Prepares Daily Fund Report
- Prepares Journal entries, cash, and inter-fund transfers.
- Daily Bank Reconciliations.
- Prepares Monthly ageing report and follow-up for payments.
- Controlled Accounts payable and accounts receivable.
- Documents preparation for Exchange and Bank Compliance.
- Daily Bank Visit and Cheques deposit in bank.
- Update client Payin and Payout in system.
- Coordinate with RMS department for Client fund limit.

<u>AREAS OF EXPERTISE</u>

Bookkeeping Taxation (TDS,GST) MIS Reporting Processing invoices **Online Banking** Auditing AP/AR Reconciliations Staff Salary Cash

PERSONAL DETAILS

Father: HafizUddin DOB: 31st Oct. 1980

Married: Yes

Native Place : Meerut U.P Nationality: Indian Language : Hindi, English Expected CTC :Negotiable Notice Period :Immediate Passport No : U6428295 Passport Validity: Yes

SOFTWARE SKILLS

TDS Software

(Spectrum, webtel)

Accounting Package

(TallyERP, Busy, Zoho)

MS Office

Excel (Advance Level)
Word Power Point

Broker Software

(Shilpi Capex Synergy)

c. Accounts Executive Vineet Securities Pvt. Ltd. BSZ Marg Press Area ITO, Delhi, India From February 2009 to September 2015 as

Responsibilities:

- VAT Return, Service Tax, TDS, Income Tax.
- Daily Fund Flow and Manage Exchange Payin Payout.
- Client Payment update inward and outward.
- MIS Aging Report, Budgets, Profitability, Expenses etc.)
- Bank Reconciliation including Settlement Account.
- Vendor Reconcile and Payment according budget.
- BG, LC, STL, FDR, Online Banking, Fund Transfer.
- Online Fund transfer within intercompany
- Client Payout Issue via Cheque, NEFT and RTGS

d. Business Development Manager with <u>ICICI Securities Ltd.</u>, ITO Delhi, India From Sep 2006 to Dec 2008 as

Responsibilities:

- Develop a business development blueprint and strategy for financial gain.
- Arrange business development meeting with prospective clients.
- Develop agent hiring & build a team of agents.
- Improve agent productivity & Arrange training about products.
- Periodical customer meet to understand customer pulse & need Ensure customer queries are responded to satisfactorily.
- Managing records of sales, revenue, and other important data
- Solve client query and Build a healthy relationship with clients

e. Accounts Assistant with <u>Abhipra Capital Ltd.</u> Azadpur Delhi, India From Jan 2004 to August 2006

Responsibilities:

- Bank Inter company Accounts Reconciliation
- Voucher entry (Journal, Received and Payments)
- Preparing fund Payin via Cheque and NEFT

f. Office Coordinator with <u>Capco International Ltd.</u> Delhi, India From Apr 2003 to Dec 2003

Responsibilities:

- Coordinate with branches and update report.
- Solve client query over phone and email.
- Manage and Maintain Branch expenses and Cash
- Keep records and manage files.

PROFESSIONAL EDUCATION

NCFM Capital Market Delear Module Diploma in Financial Accounting

ACADEMIC EDUCATION

M.Com from CSS University Meerut UP India

B.Com from CSS University Meerut UP India

Intermediate from Allahbad Board UP India

Metric (10th) from Allahbad Board UP India

- 1994

(I hereby affirm the information given here is true to the best of my knowledge and belief.)

Dated: Mohd.Usman

Place : Delhi